Finding Aid for the American Civil Liberties Union of Southern California Records LSC.0900
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Miscellaneous
  - New York Supreme Court Appellate Division - Third Department 2678 (Box 87, Folder 18)
  - New York Supreme Court Appellate Division - Third Department (Box 87, Folder 19)
  - New York Supreme Court Appellate Division - Second Department (Box 87, Folder 20)
  - A.L. Wirin correspondence with Alvin J. Abrams (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - Where Government May Not Trespass (Box 89, Folder 7)
  - Comments of the ACLU: August 31, 1961 (Box 89, Folder 10)
  - Civil Liberties Docket Vol. VIII, No. 3, May 1963 (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Union Free School District - Prayer in School (Box 92, Folder 21)
  - Explanation of Proposed Additions and Amendments to the California Law of Arrest (Box 92, Folder 22)
  - Opinion of Stanley Mosk - Police Practices - July 1959 to February 1962 (Box 92, Folder 23)
  - Injunction Suit Against House Committee on Un-American Activities by Florence M. Sloat (Box 92, Folder 24)
  - Nassau Country Bussing (Box 93, Folder 9)
  - Re: Barenblatt v. United States of America (Box 93, Folder 15)
  - Virgil V. Lampe v. United States of America (Box 93, Folder 16)
  - The People of the State of California v. Horace Hubbard - No. M307 (Box 93, Folder 17)
  - Resurgence of Youth Communist Activity in California (Box 93, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Lamont Case (Box 93, Folder 19)
  - News from Catholic Council on Civil Liberties (Box 93, Folder 20)
  - How Red is the Federal Council on Churches? (Box 93, Folder 21)
  - Fire and Police Research Association of Los Angeles - bulletin (Box 93, Folder 22)
  - Reasons for Opposing Proposed Constitutional Amendment for Control of Subversive Activities (Box 93, Folder 23)
  - ACLU Newspapers (Box 93, Folder 24)
  - Facts at Your Fingertips - Religion in Public Education (Box 94, Folder 14)
  - Amicus Curiae Brief filed by the American Jewish Council in the Brooklyn School Segregation Case (Balaban v. Rubin) (Box 94, Folder 15)
  - Supplement to Digest and Analysis of State Attorney General Opinions Relating to Freedom of Religion and Separation of Church and State (Box 94, Folder 16)
  - The Levering Act (Box 94, Folder 17)
  - Some Suggestions for Action Against Totalitarian Government System (Box 94, Folder 18)
  - Proposals for 1953-1954 ACLU Programs (Box 94, Folder 19)
  - Background Facts: California Test ("Loyalty") Oaths (Box 94, Folder 20)
  - How Can the Union Grow? By Jack Pemberton (Box 94, Folder 21)
  - San Diego Patriotic Society - The Truth About the ACLU (Box 94, Folder 22)
  - Southern California ACLU Questionnaire (Box 94, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence Malin and Gardiner July 1952 (Box 94, Folder 24)
  - Memo to Reitman from Baldwin - December 21, 1951 (Box 94, Folder 25)
  - News and Views July 1961 (Box 94, Folder 26)
  - ACLU of Southern California Financial Report from 1959 (Box 94, Folder 27)
  - ACLU of Southern California Statement of Cash Receipt and Expenditures - June 1960 (Box 94, Folder 28)
  - An Open Letter to the Conscience of Hollywood (Box 94, Folder 29)
  - The Bill of Rights and the Radical Right by Irving Brant (Box 94, Folder 30)
  - How to Cope with Attacks from the Fanatic Fringe (Box 94, Folder 31)
  - State of California - Governor's Code of Fair Practices (Box 94, Folder 32)
  - Newspaper Clippings - 1963 (Box 94, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous Memos (Box 94, Folder 34)
  - Dilworth Act 1955 (Box 94, Folder 35)
  - Nazi Party Publications 1963 (Box 94, Folder 36)
  - Conference Urges Tax Oath Protest 1955 (Box 94, Folder 37)
  - Development of Committees of ACLU Memo January 7, 1955 (Box 94, Folder 38)
  - Legislative Program February 20, 1958 (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Southern California Council of Protestant Churches - Assembly Bills 2214 and 1526 (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - Unruh Civil Rights Act (California Civil Code Sections 51 and 52) 1959 (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - Forest Lawn Memorial Park Cemetery and the Case of Caryl Chessman May 11, 1960 (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - Congressional Records, Remarks of Honorable Edward R. Roybal June 3, 1963 (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - Evanston - North Shore Urban League (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - ACLU Church-State Recommendations October 28, 1964 (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - Group Research Report - Barry Goldwater October 15, 1964 (Box 95, Folder 8)
  - The Open Forum (Box 95, Folder 9)
  - ACLU Legislative Action Bulletin August 14, 1964 (Box 95, Folder 10)
  - ACLU News October 1960, May 1963 (Box 95, Folder 11)
  - ACLU of Southern California (Box 95, Folder 13)
  - South Bay Chapter - Nazi Issue (Box 95, Folder 31)
  - Discussion Unlimited, Inc. - "Mississippi 1964 - A Story of Courage" (Box 95, Folder 33)
  - Emanuel Redfield (Box 95, Folder 34)
  - "Loom Up", Torrance Fire Fighters (Box 95, Folder 35)
  - NYPD Press Release June 20, 1963 (Box 95, Folder 36)
  - Lloyd Smith - ACLU Membership Letter (Box 95, Folder 37)
  - Civil Liberties 1958-1964 (Box 95, Folder 38)
  - Mark Bryan (Box 95, Folder 39)
  - Internal Rights of Union Members - June 1959 (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Statement of ACLU Concerning 1960 Census (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - National Milestone Events (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - Congressional Record - Senate (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Attorney General Edmund G. Brown Memorandum to the Press - May 20, 1957 (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Ordinance no. 1112 (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Financial Report - June 30, 1960 (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - Financial Report for 1959 (Box 96, Folder 8)
  - 1960 Goals and Activities - A Proposed Program (Box 96, Folder 9)
  - University Regulations - Use of Facilities and Privileges of Student Organizations (Box 96, Folder 10)
  - University Policy in Regards to Student Organizations (Box 96, Folder 11)
  - Civil Liberties in California - 1957 (Box 96, Folder 12)
  - Assembly Bill no. 61 (Box 96, Folder 13)
  - Assembly Constitutional Amendment no. 1 (Box 96, Folder 14)
  - Assembly Constitutional Amendment no. 9 (Box 96, Folder 15)
  - American Book Publishers Council, Inc. - Censorship Bulletin Vol. 3, No. 1 (Box 96, Folder 16)
  - Can Social Work Live Without Thought Control? (Box 96, Folder 17)
  - Statement to Editors of Orange County Newspapers - February 1961 (Box 96, Folder 18)
  - Oaths Required for Teachers - American Federation of Teachers (Box 96, Folder 19)
  - California Newsletter - Friends Committee on Legislation Vol. 6, No. 3 (Box 96, Folder 20)
  - John P. Peters v. Oreta Culp Hobby, et al - October 1954 (Box 96, Folder 21)
  - Office of the Mayor, City Hall - Council of the City of Los Angeles - April 1963 (Box 96, Folder 22)
  - The Repeal Newsletter Vol. 2, No. 1 (Box 96, Folder 23)
  - Petition to Human Rights Commission of the United Nations - April 17, 1959 (Box 96, Folder 24)
  - How Can We Achieve National Security and Maintain Individual Liberty? (Box 96, Folder 25)
  - The Case of the Five Spanish Sailors (Box 96, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous Brochures/Papers (Box 96, Folder 27)
  - Congressional Record (Box 96, Folder 28)
  - Truman: Harry Dexter White Case (Box 96, Folder 29)
  - Los Angeles Free Press (Box 96, Folder 30)
  - Seneca Indians (Box 96, Folder 31)
  - LAPD 1957 (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - Selective Service Act of 1948 (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - Program Goals 1953-1957 (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - ACLU Finances 1953-1954 (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - Illegal Search and Seizure (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - Bills Concerning Wiretapping (Box 97, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 97, Folder 7)
  - United States Immigration Laws (Box 97, Folder 8)
  - Cleveland Taft-Hartley Conspiracy Case (Box 97, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Fliers, Pamphlets (Box 97, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Publications (Box 97, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 97, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Handouts (Box 97, Folder 13)
  - Letter to the Editor 1954-1963 (Box 97, Folder 16)
  - Handbill Case - Hungarian Freedom Fighters Federation (Box 97, Folder 17)
  - List of Available ACLU Publications - November 1963 (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - Civil Liberties and FI-PO News (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - American Jewish Congress (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - Crime in California - Mid Year Summary, 1958 (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - Summary of 1958 and 1959 State Anti-Discrimination Laws (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - The Civil Rights and Civil Liberties Decisions of the US Supreme Court for the 1963-64 Term (Box 98, Folder 6)
  - Fundraising (Box 98, Folder 7)
  - Church State Committee (Box 98, Folder 8)
  - NAACP (Box 98, Folder 9)
  - ACLU Memo (Box 98, Folder 10)
  - Report of the Library Survey Committee - Spring, 1962 (Box 98, Folder 11)
  - Subversive Activities Control Board (Box 98, Folder 12)
  - A Renaissance of Freedom in California (Box 98, Folder 13)
  - Speeches (Box 98, Folder 14)
  - KNX Editorial (Box 98, Folder 15)
  - Bailleaux vs. Holmes et al (Box 98, Folder 16)
  - The Men of Good Will (Box 98, Folder 17)
  - Levittown Case (Box 98, Folder 18)
  - The Duzinski Case (Box 98, Folder 19)
  - Employment - Labor (Box 98, Folder 20)
  - The Collegian - McDaniel, Mont Debate (Box 98, Folder 21)
  - Compulsory Flag Salute in Schools (Box 98, Folder 22)
  - Adult Picture Magazines - City of Inglewood (Box 98, Folder 23)
  - International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union Correspondence; The Nation - April 27, 1964 (Box 98, Folder 24)
  - Detailed Analysis of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (Box 98, Folder 25)
  - Censorship Committee (Box 98, Folder 26)
  - LA Times - The John Birch Society - A Report (Box 98, Folder 27)
  - ACLU News (Box 98, Folder 28)
  - ACLU Action on HUAC (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - City University of New York (Box 100, Folder 4)
  - Support of Machinists Expelled by Union (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - Membership Income (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - The School Bus Question (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - Jimmy Hoffa (Box 100, Folder 8)
  - Draft of Amicus Brief on Clear and Present Danger Issue (Box 100, Folder 9)
  - National Defense Education Act (Box 100, Folder 10)
  - Reinstatement Plan of Dismissed Government Employees - Newspaper Clippings (Box 100, Folder 11)
  - School Integration (Box 100, Folder 12)
  - Group Research Report (Box 100, Folder 13)
  - ACLU Finances (Box 100, Folder 14)
  - Inter-Guild 1963 (Box 100, Folder 15)
  - Healy Ban at UCLA (Box 100, Folder 16)
  - University of California, Berkeley (Box 100, Folder 17)
  - Proposition 14 (Box 100, Folder 18)
- Legislative summaries
  - Congress -- 246, [3 folders.] (Box 35, Folder 14, Box 36)
  - California legislation (pre-1955) -- 247, [2 folders.] (Box 36, Folder 3-4)
  - California legislation (1955) -- 248 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Key bills in California legislation (1955) -- 249 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Party platforms -- 249.1 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Democratic Party statements -- 249.1 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Ballots and propositions -- 249.2 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - California legislation (1957) -- 249.3 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Radio addresses - Heist -- 253.2 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Radio broadcast scripts and speeches -- 253.2 (Box 37, Folder 3)
- Organizational materials
  - Bibliographies -- 254 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Bill-of-Rights Week -- 255 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Group dynamics -- 256 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Resolutions -- 256.1 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Program aids -- 256.3 (Box 38, Folder 1)
- Publications
  - I.F. Stone (1953) -- 257 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - I.F. Stone (1954) -- 258 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - I.F. Stone (1955) -- 259 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - I.F. Stone (1956) -- 260 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - I.F. Stone (1957) -- 261 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - I.F. Stone (1958) -- 262 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Liberal Democrat -- 269 (Box 38, Folder 8)
- Liberal groups
  - Liberal groups -- L0 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Alianzo Hispano-Americana -- L1 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - American Committee for Cultural Freedom -- L4 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - AFL -- L5 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - American Federation of Teachers (AFT) -- L6 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - ADA -- L7 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - American Friends Service Committee -- L8 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - American Jewish Congress -- L9, [3 folders.] (Box 39, Folder 1-3)
  - B'nai B'rith Anti-defamation League (ADL) -- L11 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Bay Area Committee for the Revision of the Walter-McCarran Act (the 1952 Immigration & Nationality Act) -- L12 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Bellamy Club -- L13 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Bill of Rights Fund -- L14 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - California Committee for Fair Employment Practices (FEP) -- L15 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - California Emergency Defense Committee -- L16 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Californians for the Bill of Rights -- L18 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Californians for Liberal Representation -- L18.1 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - California Legislative Conference -- L19 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Catholic Council on Civil Liberties -- L19.1 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - CIO -- L20 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Citizen's Committee to Preserve American Freedoms -- L21 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Civil Rights Congress (CRC) -- L22 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Committee to Repeal the Dilworth Act -- L23 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Committee for the Return of Confiscated German and Japanese Property -- L24 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - L.A. County Committee on Human Relations -- L25 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Council for Condemned -- L27 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Council for Mexican-American Affairs -- L28 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee -- L29 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Everybody's Committee to Outlaw War -- L31 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Fair Campaign Practices -- L32 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Fellowship of Concerned -- L33 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Federation for Repeal of the Levering Act -- L34 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Fellowship of Reconciliation (FOR) -- L35 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Freedom Agenda -- L36 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Fund for the Republic -- L37 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - National Friends Committee on Legislation -- L37.1 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - California Friends Committee on Legislation -- L37.2 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Japanese American Citizens League (JACL) -- L38 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Joe Crail Bill of Rights Week -- L39 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Los Angeles County Conference on Community Relations (LACCCR) -- L40 (folder 1 of 3) (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Los Angeles County Conference on Community Relations (LACCCR) -- L40 (folder 2 of 3) (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Los Angeles County Conference on Community Relations (LACCCR) -- L40 (folder 3 of 3) (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Leadership Conference on Civil Rights (LCCR) -- L40.1 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - L.A. Citizens Committee for Public Schools -- L41 (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - L.A. Committee for the Protection of the Foreign-born -- L42 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - L.A. Committee for Equal Employment Opportunities -- L43 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - L.A. Conference on Immigration and Citizenship -- L44 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - L.A. County Civil Liberties Clearing House -- L45 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - League of Women Voters -- L46 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Methodist Federation for Social Action -- L47 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Musicians Guild of America -- L48 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - NAACP -- L49 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - National Citizens Committee on Immigration and Citizenship -- L50 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - National Civil Liberties Clearing House -- L51 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - National Committee Relations Advisory Council -- L52 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews -- L53 (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - National Federation for Constitutional Liberties -- L53.5 (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - National Lawyers Guild -- L54 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Non-government Organization of UN -- L55 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - NVA Against Nuclear Weapons -- L56 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Presbyterians -- L57 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Religion and Labor Council of L.A. -- L58 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Religious Freedom Committee -- L59 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Sane Nuclear Policy -- L59.1 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Servicemen's Defense Committee -- L60 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Socialist Party -- L61 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Southland Jewish Organization -- L62 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - "New South" - Publication of Southern Regional Council -- L63.1 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Student Civil Liberties Conference -- L64 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Unitarians -- L65 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - United World Federalists -- L66 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Veteran's Group Against Loyalty Oaths -- L67 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Women for Legal Action -- L68 (Box 43, Folder 16)
- Right groups
  - Right groups -- R1 (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - "Americans, On Guard" -- R1.5 (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - American Legion -- R2 (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Daughters of American Colonists -- R3 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Gerald L.K. Smith -- R4, [2 folders.] (Box 44, Folder 2-3)
  - "Cross and the Flag" (1955-1956) -- R4.1 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - "Cross and the Flag" (1957) -- R4.1 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Keep America -- R5 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Fifield -- R6 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Merchants and Manufacturers -- R7 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Minute Men (Gen. Holdridge) -- R8 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Neo-fascist groups (30's) -- R9 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Women of the Pacific -- R10 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Christian Anti-communist Crusade -- R11 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Rockwell -- R12 (Box 45, Folder 1)
- American Civil Liberties Union
  - Chicago Division ACLU -- A1 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Radio-TV Panel: (1955-1958) Minutes, workpapers, press releases -- A1 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Colorado Branch, ACLU -- A2 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - "Colorado Civil Liberties" publication -- A2.1 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Detroit Branch, ACLU of Michigan -- A3 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Florida CLU -- A4 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Illinois Division, ACLU -- A5, [2 folders.] (Box 45, Folder 8, Box 46)
  - Illinois publication "The Brief" -- A5.1 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Indiana ACLU -- A6 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Iowa ACLU -- A7 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Louisiana ACLU -- A8 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Maryland ACLU -- A9 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Maryland publication -- A9.1 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Massachusetts ACLU -- A10 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Minnesota Branch, ACLU -- A11 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - New Haven ACLU -- A12 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - New York State ACLU (NYCLU) -- A13 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - NYCLU publication -- A13.1 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Northern California ACLU -- A14 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Northern California ACLU -- A14 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Northern California ACLU - Ernest Besig, Director -- A14 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Northern California publication -- A14.1, [2 folders.] (Box 47, Folder 3-4)
  - Ohio (Cincinnati and Cleveland) ACLU -- A15 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Ohio publication -- A15.1 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Greater Philadelphia Branch, ACLU -- A16 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Philadelphia publication "Civil Liberties Record" -- A16.1 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - St. Louis, ACLU -- A17 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Washington State Chapter, ACLU -- A18 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Washington State publication -- A18.1 (Box 48, Folder 2)
- Criticisms of ACLU
  - Criticisms of ACLU -- A20 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Criticisms of ACLU -- A20 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - ACLU - Controversial organization -- A20 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Praise of ACLU -- A21 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - History of ACLU -- A22 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    FOLDER CONTAINS UNPROCESSED DIGITAL MATERIALS: Materials will require assessment and may need further processing for safe access. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
    Scope and Contents
    This folder contains one History of ACLU of Southern California 1923-2013 DATA-CD of text by Nat Segaloff.
  - Integration and finance problems of ACLU -- A25 (Box 49, Folder 1)
- National ACLU committees
  - Academic freedom -- A26.1 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Alien / Indian civil rights -- A26.2 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Due process -- A26.3 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Equality -- A26.4 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - International civil liberties -- A26.5 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Labor -- A26.6 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Free speech -- A26.7 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Projects and activities -- A27 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Resolutions and policies -- A28, [2 folders.] (Box 49, Folder 1, Box 50)
  - Public relations -- A29 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Public statements - press releases - (1954-1955) -- A30.1 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Public statements - press releases - (1956) -- A30.2 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Public statements - press releases - (1957) -- A30.3 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Public statements - press releases - (1958) -- A30.4 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Marshall Trust Fund -- A31 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - "Civil Liberties Quarterly" -- A32 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - "Civil Liberties" -- A32 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - National Board of Directors - Minutes (1948-1952) -- A33.1 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - National Board of Directors - Minutes (1953) -- A33.2 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - National Board of Directors - Minutes (1954) -- A33.3 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - National Board of Directors - Minutes (1955) -- A33.4 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - National Board of Directors - Minutes (1956) -- A33.5 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - National Board of Directors - Minutes (1957) -- A33.6 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - National Board of Directors - Minutes (1958) -- A33.7 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - National Board of Directors - Minutes (1960) -- A33.9 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Corliss Lamont Controversy -- A34 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Policy on statements of witnesses before investigating committees -- A35 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Chicago conference on finance, March '55 -- A36 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - N.Y. correspondence -- A37 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Biennial conference minutes (1954) -- A38.1 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Biennial conference minutes (1958) -- A38.2 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - 1940 Resolution -- A39 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Reaffirmation of Purpose (1954) -- A39.1 (Box 52, Folder 7)
- ACLU of Southern California
  - Board of Directors -- A50 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Interim Committee, minutes (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Board of Directors, minutes (prior to 1958) -- A50.2 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Executive Committee, minutes of meetings (prior to 1958) -- A50.3 (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Board of Directors, minutes (1958-1963) -- A50.5 (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Academic freedom -- A51.09 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Censorship Committee -- A51.099 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Civil Rights Committee -- A51.0999 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Legislative action -- A51.2 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Bill of Rights Day -- A51.5 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Arts division -- A51.7 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Immigration and deportation -- A51.8 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Minority party rights -- A52 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Nominating committee -- A52.1 (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - "The Open Forum" -- A52.2 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Finance -- A53 (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - Statements -- A53 (Box 53, Folder 12)
  - Tax records, 1960 -- A53 (Box 53, Folder 13)
  - Membership committee -- A54 (Box 53, Folder 14)
  - Materials used to attract members -- A54.1 (Box 53, Folder 15)
  - 1958 USC Institute -- A55.1 (Box 53, Folder 16)
  - Public meetings -- A57 (Box 53, Folder 17)
  - Planning committee -- A58 (Box 53, Folder 18)
  - Branch statements - News releases -- A59 (Box 53, Folder 19)
  - History - Old by-laws, etc. -- A60 (Box 53, Folder 20)
  - History - Old finance records / Auditor's reports -- A60 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Chapter guide -- A60.1 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - By-laws and Board policy -- A60.2 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Chapter conferences -- A60.3 (Box 54, Folder 4)
- Affiliates
  - Arizona -- F1 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Illinois -- F2 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Massachusetts -- F3 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Michigan -- F4 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Northern California -- F5 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Washington, D.C. -- F6 (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Florida, 1962 -- F7 (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - New York -- F11 (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - Oregon -- F13 (Box 54, Folder 13)